[Music]
welcome Chris and Oliver are narrowing
each of their teams to the five
strongest artists one more artist from
each team will be eliminated before all
of you battle each other last week team
Peck competed so team Nunez you're up
for elimination this is your last chance
to make it into Chris's top five one of
you will not be a part of that this week
we're testing artistry artistry is the
creativity that you're able to present
in a tattoo without artistry you're
unable to make something awesome right
now more than 16 million Americans
suffer from diseases caused by
cigarettes in the last 50 years more
than 20 million Americans have died from
smoking your canvases today have quit
smoking but they're still paying the
price they all have permanent scars as a
result today you must help your canvases
by making their scars disappear covering
scars is really really hard some scars
do not hold any pigment at all and
sometimes it gets raised and puffed up
and even more obvious than it was in the
first place
today's an important day these people
already have a lot that they're dealing
with and these scars remind them of
their health battles in the past and now
it's your chance to turn your drawing
skills on and camouflage their scars if
there's any of y'all that still smoke
today's a day to really really the rest
of your life
bring out your canvases
all right team pack that not only are
you safe from elimination this week but
you're also calling the shots you get to
assign the canvases for this flash
challenge as a team pick one person to
talk to the canvases on behalf of the
team then discuss your plan yeah going
up Mike how you guys doing
what are we doing for your a themed
castle Titans the dragon okay
there is a huge scar going right up the
center of this guy's chest I do not want
that
Nina color realism now see me pointing
to a black hole which will mean my
Stella I hope I do not get the guy with
the trach in his neck because that is
super scary and I do not want to be
responsible for that area tree life
heaven length black and gray with green
leaves
a biomechanical theme mom I know okay
from probably than me kept up okay this
guy doesn't have just one little scar
the entire surface is one big scarf
we're gonna give these people the best
tattoos that they can get because the
flash challenge not an elimination
challenge okay we're totally looking
past teaming uses negative attitude and
the amount of times they've screwed us
over this is not the day to do that all
right guys one by one please read the
artist's name on the bottom of your
skull
sketchy lawyer Kevin
Aaron this is gonna be tough what
happened tough Tito Nicky seriously a
castle with a dragon Kelly is the one
that knows how to do really whimsical
pretty things what the hell is going on
Kalli the winner of this flash challenge
will have the power to assign all human
canvases in the Elimination tattoo you
will have six hours to help your canvas
by transforming their scar and your time
begins now
[Music]
that's 14 thanks to cancer working on a
scar you can't just draw whatever you
normally draw and stick it anywhere you
have to take into consideration what's
already there before you design it how
long did this work for I started out as
13 and I won cancer was a 39 how much do
you smoke you smoke welcome back today
that's crazy I had to have my lung
removed because of it definitely makes
me want with it
heavily scarred skin is unpredictable so
a combination of artistry and experience
is gonna win you just told that you're
one of the top artists here you'll do a
killer job yeah okay believe me to it
Nikki won't even talk to us like she's
so angry she's literally fuming
Nikki's great was the dark gothic
cathedral cuz I thought she made happy
let's do it
you are thinking like what like a tree
off like I said last week we might to
your life I think I drove the boat I
would have never expected you to do this
solid plaque in a tombstone shape like
if this happened at home in my shop I
would my pants
how are gonna redeem myself with another
tree of life over us card I'm gonna be
honest I want to give you something more
stronger for powerful like a dragon
here's an idea let's do it we're gonna
do a Japanese dragon I need to play it
safe five more hours five more hours
I've always wanted something like that
I'm alone anything this is easily one of
the most important tattoos I've done in
my entire career it's really just it's
get freaked out about it you know what
everybody its picture they can get
freaked out about it this guy is 21
years old and he has a hole in his
throat that children are afraid of here
we go this is my chance to make it just
a little bit better everybody's gonna be
looking at your net now gonna go weigh
that out
[Music]
superstrate okay tell me stuff about
strong scars have major tissue damage so
it's not an easy thing to endure 15 my
canvas taps I'm gonna be so bummed out
not just for her but for myself I want
to win this challenge the girls are
getting tighter every day we can't let
them get too far ahead of themselves
fortunately my canvas he's been through
so many surgeries his nerves are all
that one moment is fine the next moment
he's in excruciating pain I might not be
able to finish this tattoo we'll get
through it them
five four three two one that's it times
up machines down no more ink
oh my god that's gorgeous that is
beautiful we are
Kelly's throat scar cover-up looks like
a space jellyfish no way she's gonna win
the skull pick today thank you all right
time to critique your work and we will
start with Kelly how was it sitting with
Kelly
I understand not wanting to do a big
black hole leading into a dark hole that
was definitely a smart sensible play but
when I first look at it you don't get
this immediate sense of space and
galaxies the way you worked with the
skin in that area you have some amazing
color blends saturated color and really
bright color play but you don't really
get a space feel from a distance when
you look at it Eric you used his muscle
shapes to contour the mechanisms you put
in there definitely shows artistry you
did some really clean strong outlining
even though it's thin it works really
well with the contrast I think you did a
great job thank you sketch you lawyer
this tattoo came out super slick runs
right up the middle of the scar the
feather texture really hides the scar
tissue from a distance to letterings a
little busy it's a little bit hard to
read but once you get up on it it's
super tight technically done Kevin this
is that too overall looks really smooth
the nice texture in the fur even over
top of the heavy scarred areas you got
the same amount of nice shading over the
top of the scar versus where the scar
wasn't it's a quality tattoo thank you
Peter
he definitely hid the scar but as far as
the overall shape of the tattoo the way
it fit on the back it was a very odd
placement it's really not
he has a pretty considerable dividend in
his back so to place it where it is fit
the flow of the back and definitely fit
the direction of the scar in my opinion
it looks pretty good man Nicky he had
this crazy weird dragging he made what
he had a lot better and you got rid of
the scar the way that you used the scar
tissue to play into that rocky texture
to camouflage it all and tie it in
really good all of the boys in this
house are definitely gunning for the
girls if I don't win this skull pick I'm
completely screwed hey YouTube it's
Chris Nunez don't forget to subscribe to
spikes Channel